<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on ~/bermudev/blog</title>
    <link>https://bermu.dev/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on ~/bermudev/blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Carlos Bermúdez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:41:53 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bermu.dev/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Pyenv to Manage Different Python Versions</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/using_pyenv_to_manage_different_python_versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:41:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/using_pyenv_to_manage_different_python_versions/</guid>
      <description>When working with different projects it is common to have different versions of the same programming language and dependencies for each one of them, so if we had a single installation or global version, this could give constant conflict between different projects.
To fix that we can use tools like pyenv and virtual environments. What these tools do is to isolate different versions of python and different installations (environments) of each of these versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick overview of Test Driven Development</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/a_quick_overview_of_test_driven_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 23:18:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/a_quick_overview_of_test_driven_development/</guid>
      <description>Test-Driven Development (TDD) is a software development practice where developers write tests before writing the implementation code. Yes, I know it sounds a little crazy, but keep reading!
What is TDD all about? The TDD cycle is really simple and it usually consists of three main steps:
Write a failing test: First, you write a test that specifies the desired behavior of the code you are about to write. This test is expected to fail initially, as the code to fulfill this behavior has not been implemented yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre-commit Hooks in Python</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/pre-commit_hooks_in_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 19:32:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/pre-commit_hooks_in_python/</guid>
      <description>Last month I was talking about code formatters, tools that help to unify styles in our code, making it cleaner, unified, and helping when working in a team.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about how to integrate those tools into our workflow, so that we make sure we always use them. For this we will use what is known as Pre-commit hooks.
What are Pre-commit Hooks? Pre-commit hooks are scripts or tools that run automatically before each commit is made in a version control system, such as Git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing code formatters: Black and YAPF</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/introducing_code_formatters_black_and_yapf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 18:42:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/introducing_code_formatters_black_and_yapf/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are in a development group where you work on common projects, you do tasks on the same files and everyone has their own way of doing things, their own style preference, etc. The amount of noise that is generated in PRs is incredible.
Thankfully, there are tools available that can automatically format our code according to a defined style guide. I will talk about two of the most popular code formatters for Python: Black and YAPF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruff: A Fast Rust-based Python Linter</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/ruff-a-fast-rust-based-python-linter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 14:46:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/ruff-a-fast-rust-based-python-linter/</guid>
      <description>In recent weeks there has been considerable talk in the Python community about a new linter that may come to replace the already more than consolidated Flake8 or Pylint. This new linter is called Ruff.
What is Ruff? Ruff is a linting tool for Python, that like all other linters, analyzes your code for potential errors, style violations, and other issues that could impact the quality and readability of your code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
