<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development tools on ~/bermudev/blog</title>
    <link>https://bermu.dev/tags/development-tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development tools on ~/bermudev/blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Carlos Bermúdez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:41:53 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bermu.dev/tags/development-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Pyenv to Manage Different Python Versions</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/using_pyenv_to_manage_different_python_versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:41:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/using_pyenv_to_manage_different_python_versions/</guid>
      <description>When working with different projects it is common to have different versions of the same programming language and dependencies for each one of them, so if we had a single installation or global version, this could give constant conflict between different projects.
To fix that we can use tools like pyenv and virtual environments. What these tools do is to isolate different versions of python and different installations (environments) of each of these versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices Development with DevContainer in VSCode</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/microservices_development_with_devcontainer_in_vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 16:28:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/microservices_development_with_devcontainer_in_vscode/</guid>
      <description>I have recently started working on a new project with microservices and I have come across one of the tools that has impressed me the most in this time. This tool is the DevContainer extension in Visual Studio Code (VSCode), and now I will explain why I think it is indispensable for working in microservices development.
What is DevContainer? DevContainer is an extension provided by VSCode that allows developers to define and manage development environments within a container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing code formatters: Black and YAPF</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/introducing_code_formatters_black_and_yapf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 18:42:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/introducing_code_formatters_black_and_yapf/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are in a development group where you work on common projects, you do tasks on the same files and everyone has their own way of doing things, their own style preference, etc. The amount of noise that is generated in PRs is incredible.
Thankfully, there are tools available that can automatically format our code according to a defined style guide. I will talk about two of the most popular code formatters for Python: Black and YAPF.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
