<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on ~/bermudev/blog</title>
    <link>https://bermu.dev/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on ~/bermudev/blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Carlos Bermúdez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 14:46:02 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bermu.dev/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ruff: A Fast Rust-based Python Linter</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/ruff-a-fast-rust-based-python-linter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 14:46:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/ruff-a-fast-rust-based-python-linter/</guid>
      <description>In recent weeks there has been considerable talk in the Python community about a new linter that may come to replace the already more than consolidated Flake8 or Pylint. This new linter is called Ruff.
What is Ruff? Ruff is a linting tool for Python, that like all other linters, analyzes your code for potential errors, style violations, and other issues that could impact the quality and readability of your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Dog Shelter API with Flask and Python</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/building-a-dog-shelter-api-with-flask-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 16:21:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/building-a-dog-shelter-api-with-flask-and-python/</guid>
      <description>One of the first projects I did when I started in the world of backend development was an API for a dog shelter using Django REST Framework, it is one of my first projects and although I remember it fondly I have learned a lot since then.
So I thought, why not try doing something similar using another framework? This way I can take the opportunity to dive more into API development, learn about a different framework and revisit an old project that I&amp;rsquo;m so close to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandas for Data Analisys</title>
      <link>https://bermu.dev/posts/pandas-for-data-analisys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 12:06:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bermu.dev/posts/pandas-for-data-analisys/</guid>
      <description>In my professional career I have had to work with large amounts of data and I have been able to learn how to use some analysis tools, one of them is Pandas. So, why don&amp;rsquo;t we take a look at what Pandas is and what it offers us?
What is Pandas? Pandas is a library for data analysis and data manipulation in Python. It provides data structures and functions needed to work on structured data seamlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
